Maia Williams

Spatial Data Specialist

CONTACT

2/29 Trusting Lane White Gum Valley, 6162, WA mw@maia.id.au 0412 267 802

ONLINE

LinkedIn

Online resources

OSM

Wikipedia

Wikidata

EDUCATION

Master of Landscape Architecture

University of Western Australia 2017 – 2020

Master of Science (Geospatial Technologies)

Universidade Nova de Lisboa and Westfälische Wilhelms-Universität Münster 2009 – 2011

Bachelor of Engineering (Environmental) and Bachelor of Science (Physics)

University of Western Australia 2000 – 2006

EXPERTISE

QGIS

ArcGIS Desktop | Server | Online GPS devices | Fulcrum | QField

AutoCAD

InDesign | Illustrator | Photoshop

ABS TableBuilder Pro

Cross-disciplinary communication Scientific writing

PROFILE

Experienced in spatial data analysis and spatial thinking within multidisciplinary contexts. Interested in exploring people – place connections from many perspectives and contemplating implications for urban design. Excited by investigating landscapes and systems within them.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GIS Analyst

Mammoth Geospatial | January 2022 - present

Spatial data analysis and mapping.

Freelance Spatial Data Specialist

Various | August 2017 - present

Spatial data acquisition and analysis, spatial infrastructure setup and Geographic Information System (GIS) training services.

GIS Officer

Yilka Heritage and Land Care | August 2017 - present

Managing spatial data repository, and providing mapping and data analysis services to anthropologists, lawyers and native title holders/board members.

Spatial Data Analyst/Designer

Syrinx | June 2018 - March 2022

Spatial data analysis and design.

Studio Tutor and Guest Tutor

UWA School of Design | February 2020 - present

GIS Officer

Central Desert Native Title Services Group | June 2014 - July 2017

GIS Officer

Department of Water — Spatial Science and GIS Section | October 2013 – May 2014

Geospatial Systems Officer

Department of Planning | September 2012 - June 2013

GIS Project Officer

State Heritage Office | May 2012 - September 2012

Australian Youth Ambassador for Development (AYAD) Volunteer Researcher

Institute of Geoecology, Mongolian Academy of Sciences | 2008 - 2009

Environmental Officer

Department of Water - Salinity Section | 2007 - 2008

VOLUNTEERING

Geogeeks

https://geogeeks.org | 2021 - present

Co-organiser of fortnightly open geospatial meetups and mapping days. Working on communications, funding administration, venue booking, speaker selection and co-hosting meetups.

2021 FOSS4G SotM Oceania - Perth Hub

https://foss4g-perth.org | 2021

Co-organiser of the two day FOSS4G SotM Oceania conference held in Perth, November 2021.

AWARDS

UWA School of Design studio prizes | 2017 and 2019

AILA Festival student representative | 2018

Erasmus Mundus scholarship | 2009 - 2011

Australasian Institute of Mining and Metallurgy Scholarship | 2000 - 2005

PUBLICATIONS, PROJECTS and DISSERTATIONS

Resource development

Data analysis and spatial data resources for landscape architects (primarily UWA students).

Presentation

Williams, M. (2023). Populating Wikipedia: Keeping population figures up-to-date in place articles, February 2022 (Unpublished). Available at https://wikimedia.org.au/wiki/Populating_Wikipedia: New_tool_integrating_Australian_Census_data (Accessed 27 June 2023).

Blog post

Williams, M. (2022). Populating Wikipedia: New tool integrating Australian Census data, Wikimedia Australia, 21 July 2022 [Blog]. Available at https://wikimedia.org.au/wiki/Populating_Wikipedia: New tool integrating_Australian_Census_data (Accessed 27 June 2023).

Journal article

Williams, M., Kuhn W. and Painho M. (2012). The influence of landscape variation on landform categorization, *Journal of Spatial Information Science*, Iss. 5, 51-73. Available at https://josis.org/index.php/josis/article/view/30 (Accessed 27 June 2023)

Dissertations